== 字幕制作：眼红红==
俄罗斯帝国\n1874年
大人，这个用来做什么？
What should I do with\nthis, Your Excellency?
是
Yes.
这个是我为达里亚亚历山祖拿\n和孩子们挑选的
I picked it out for Daria Alexandrovna\nand the children.
你好，莉莉
Lili.
你好，格里沙
Grisha.
华斯亚
Vasya.
谁会来看祖母？
Who is coming to see Grand-maman?
我！我！我！
Me! Me! Me!
来吧，孩子们
Come along, my little ducklings.
今天要乖，我走了
Be good today. I'm off.
仔细阅读这一章
Read the chapter carefully.
我会回来考你
I'll come back to test you on it.
读两遍
Read it twice.
噢，史蒂华
Oh, Stiva.
多莉姨发现了\n家庭教师写的纸条
Aunt Dolly found a note\nfrom the governess.
怎样？
Well?
史蒂华要我去莫斯科\n劝多莉原谅他
Stiva wants me to come to Moscow\nto persuade Dolly to forgive him.
我会被迫与妻子分开\n好让通奸可被原谅？
I'm to be deprived of my wife\nso that adultery may be forgiven?
我不能原谅他\n只因他是你哥哥
I can't excuse him\njust because he's your brother.
也是为了多莉的缘故
Oh, it's for Dolly's sake, too.
今天有四个委员会
Four committees today.
全世界在等着我
I have the world waiting for me.
没有时间看你的练习
There's never time to\nlook at your exercises.
大人，史奥沙表现非常好
Serozha is doing very\nwell, Your Excellency.
谁给你穿这件衬衫？
Who put this shirt on you?
没关系，我会来听你读书
Well, never mind. I'll\ncome and hear you read.
也许明天吧
Tomorrow, perhaps.
谢谢你，卢基治，也许明天吧
Thank you, Lukich. Perhaps tomorrow.
不，明天不能
No. No, no, not tomorrow.
谢谢你，大人
Thank you, Your Excellency.
来吧
Come along.
阿历士，你认为\n九年的婚姻和子女
Alexei, do you think\nnine years of marriage and children
是痴心的证明吗？
should count for nothing\nagainst an infatuation?
不，好吧
No. Very well.
但罪是有代价的，你肯定知道
But sin has a price, you\nmay be sure of that.
但为什么呢？
But why?
因为多莉姨就住在那里
Because that's where Aunt Dolly lives.
-但为什么呢？\n-史奥沙，我已告诉你
- But why?\n- I told you, Serozha.
她不舒服，我一定要去看看她
She's not well. I must go to see her.
但为什么，妈妈？
But why, Mama?
不要令妈妈哭
Don't make Mama cry.
我会很快回来\n并带一份礼物给你
I'll be back before you know,\nand bring you a present.
我不想要礼物，我想你留下来
I don't want a present.\nI want you to stay.
噢，我的宝贝
Oh, my little
什么礼物？
What present?
这样好多了
That's better.
这是我第一次离开我的小孩
It's the first time I've\nleft my little boy.
你离开你的儿子\n而我便回去看我的
So, you're leaving your son\nand I'm returning to mine.
我是弗隆斯加亚伯爵夫人
I'm Countess Vronskaya.
我曾到圣彼得堡\n参加孙女的洗礼
I've been in St. Petersburg\nfor the christening of a granddaughter.
我的大儿子娶了齐高夫公主
My eldest son married Princess Chirkov.
你很迷人\n为什么我不认识你？
You're a charming creature.\nWhy don't I know you?
我从没有到过莫斯科社交场合
I've never been in Moscow society, really.
但你知道我的名字
But you know my name.
-我听过你提及\n-你意思是谈及？
- I've heard you mentioned.\n- Talked about, you mean?
爱情
Ah, love.
-是爱情吗？\n-永远都是
- Was it love?\n- Always.
儿子们因我感到羞愧
My sons are ashamed of me.
我宁愿最终希望我没有\n好过最终希望我有
But I'd rather end up wishing I\nhadn't than end up wishing I had.
你同意吗？
Wouldn't you?
我不知道
I don't know.
大人，有些人无预约来的
Some man came\nwithout an appointment, Your Excellency.
在外面等着
Waiting outside.
列文！你去了哪里？
Levin! Where did you disappear?
我很渴望见你
I'm very anxious to see you.
我需要你的意见
I need your advice.
那么来我的房间吧
Well, come into my room, then.
这是我最老的朋友\n康斯坦丁德米特里维治列文
This is my oldest friend,\nKonstantin Dmitrievich Levin.
传口讯我会迟几分钟
Someone send word I'll\nbe a few minutes late.
我的办公室就在上面
That's my office, up there.
我一直在埋头苦干，坐下
Oh, I've been hard at it. Sit down.
苦干什么？
Hard at what, exactly?
我们工作应接不暇
Well, we're overwhelmed with work.
文书工作
Paperwork.
文书是俄国的灵魂\n耕作只是个胃
Paperwork is the soul of Russia.\nFarming is only the stomach.
我什么时候来打猎些鹬？
Now, when am I going to\ncome and shoot some snipe?
看看你，穿着西部的衣服\n你说过永远不再穿的
Look at you, in Western clothes\nyou told me you'd never wear again.
有事发生
Something's up.
是的，我恋爱了，我回来求婚
Yes, I'm in love. I've\ncome back to propose.
你猜到她是谁吗？
Have you guessed who she is?
我有怀疑\n当你在这儿时，为什么不求婚？
I... I have a suspicion.\nWhy didn't you propose when you were here?
我当时觉得不可能
I decided it was impossible.
基蒂是来自天堂的天使\n而我来自地上
Kitty is of the heavens, an angel.\nAnd I am of the earth.
但我想了又想\n没有她我人生没意义
But then, I thought and thought,\nand there's no life for me without her.
-我还有机会吗？\n-当然有
- Do I have a chance?\n- Of course you do.
舒巴斯基家\n今晚有个晚会
The Shcherbatskys\nare giving a soiree this evening.
要早到，在众人到之前
Get there early, before the crowd.
-我建议你…\n-好，是什么？
- And if I may suggest...\n- Anything, what?
-新靴\n-对，还有别的吗？
- New boots.\n- Right. Anything else?
我们一起吃晚餐
We'd better have dinner together.
来吧，我们稍后在英伦餐馆见
Come on. We'll meet later at l'Angleterre.
或你喜欢冬宫餐馆？
Or do you prefer the Hermitage?
不如5点30分在英伦餐馆
Let's say, 5:30 at l'Angleterre.
我欠他们多过冬宫餐馆
I owe them more than the Hermitage,
所以不去是不公平的
so it wouldn't be fair\nto withdraw my custom.
记得新靴子、外套和恰当的帽子
Uh, so, new boots, coat, and a proper hat.
对不起、对不起、对不起
Excuse me. Excuse me. Excuse me.
你…
Do you...
对不起
Excuse me.
很不公平
It's so unfair.
你为了爱情而结婚
You marry for love.
你是个好丈夫
You're a good husband.
孩子们出世，数年相隔的
Children arrive, years depart.
一下子，你的妻子变老和疲惫
And all of a sudden,\nyour wife grows old and tired.
她的头发稀薄，而她的身体…
And her hair is thin. And her body...
而你，你还有活力！
And you yourself, you\nstill have your vigor!
然后你发现自己\n被这么多的女人分心
And then you find yourself\na martyr to distraction by so many women.
原谅我，但我觉得这是难以理解
Forgive me, but I find\nthat incomprehensible.
就好像我要离开这餐厅\n去面包店偷个面包
As though, I should leave this restaurant\nand steal a roll from a baker's shop.
一个新鲜出炉面包
Well, you know, a freshly baked roll.
我说的是爱情\n而你在谈你的食欲
I'm talking about love,\nand you're talking about your appetite.
很容易混浠的\n你认识弗龙斯基伯爵吗？
Easily confused.\nNow, do you know, um, Count Vronsky?
谁？不认识，为何问？
Who? No. Why?
他是你的对手\n你走后，他从彼得堡来了
He's your rival. He turned up\nfrom Petersburg after you left.
他是谁？
Who is he?
你不需要担心他\n他只是…
Oh, you don't need to worry about him.\nHe's... He's just...
他是个富有、英俊的骑兵军官
He's a rich, good-looking cavalry officer
他没有更好的事做\n除了与漂亮女人做爱
who has nothing better to do\nthan make love to pretty women.
那是椰菜汤吗？
Is that cabbage soup?
俄罗斯椰菜汤\n正如先生所叫的\nPotage aux choux à la russe,
as the gentleman ordered.
这是我想要的
It's what I wanted.
你要明白，对于我来说\n今晚是生死攸关的
Understand that, for me,\ntonight is a question of life and death.
康斯亚…
Kostya...
康斯亚，如果基蒂拒绝你\n她便是疯的
Kostya, Kitty would be mad to refuse you.
多莉站在你那边，你知道吗？
And Dolly's on your side, you know?
她说她妹妹基蒂\n一直想做你妻子，并将会做
She says her sister Kitty was always\nmeant to be your wife, and will be.
多莉这样说？
Dolly said that?
我一直认为你的多莉是很难得的
I've always thought your Dolly was a gem.
她的确是
She is.
我爱她爱到神魂颠倒
I loved her to distraction.
康斯坦丁！
Konstantin!
我太早到，我会回来
I'm too early. I'll come back.
不，上来吧
No. Come up.
看看我
Look at me.
我代爸爸和妈妈接待\n他们迟了装扮
I'm receiving for Papa and Maman,\nwho are late to dress.
这是我第一次接待人
It's my first reception.
叶基蒂莲娜公主
Princess Ekaterina.
高兴极了、高兴极了
Delighted. Delighted.
康斯坦丁德米特里维治\n我很高兴你能够与我们一起
I'm so pleased you were able to be\nwith us, Konstantin Dmitrievich.
基蒂，你看来…
Kitty, you look...
-你看来…\n-史蒂华告诉我们你回来了
- You look...\n- Stiva told us you were back.
你会留多久？
How long are you staying?
我不知道，这取决于你
I don't know. It depends on you.
取决于我？
On me?
我意思是我…
What I mean to say is I...
我来只有一个目的
I only came with one purpose.
我想…\n你愿意做我妻子吗？
I want to... Will you be my wife?
对不起、对不起
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
错误时刻，这是错误的时刻
Wrong moment. It's the wrong moment.
但你愿意吗？
But will you?
我不能
I can't.
对不起
I'm sorry.
是的
Yes.
这是不可能的
It was impossible.
对不起
I'm sorry.
你是尼古拉列文的弟弟？
Are you the brother of Nikolai Levin?
是
Yes.
他在莫斯科\n住在奇祖夫卡的育利康
He's in Moscow.\nHe's staying at the Unicorn in Khitrovka.
你怎么知道？
How do you know?
我知道这类事情的
It's the sort of thing I know.
弗龙斯基伯爵？
Count Vronsky?
是？
Yes?
基蒂公主
Princess Kitty.
很久没见\n但似乎像昨天一样
It's been so long,\nand yet, it seems like yesterday.
就是昨天
It was yesterday.
对不起
Excuse me.
不
No.
抱歉
Sorry.
是康斯亚
It's Kostya.
天啊！看看他
Good God! Look at him.
你看似个资本家
You look like a capitalist.
你想要什么？
What do you want?
没什么，我来看看你
Nothing. I came to see you.
晚安，小姐…女士
Good evening, miss... Madam.
不要这样对她说话\n你听起来像个法官
Don't talk to her like that.\nYou sound like a magistrate.
给我弟弟更多伏特加！快点
More vodka for my brother! Quick about it.
我什么也不要
I don't want anything.
我没事
I'm all right.
谁告诉你哪里可以找到我？
Who told you where to find me?
第三部门的一名上校\n他们在监视你
A colonel in the Third Department.\nThey're watching you.
好
Good.
他们一定认为我很危险
They must think I'm dangerous.
你笑什么？
What have you got to smile about?
没什么
Nothing.
没错
That's right.
时日已到\n我已经放弃了我长子名分
The day is coming.\nI have given up my birthright for it.
你在历史的错误一方
You're on the wrong side of history.
不是因为特权是不道德
Not because privilege is immoral.
是因为它不合理
But because it's irrational.
他有病！
He's sick!
如果你知什么对你好，便放手
Let go, if you know what's good for you.
我把玛丽亚尼古拉娜\n从妓院带出来
I took Marya Nikolaevna from a brothel.
但我视她为妻
But I consider her my wife.
如果她的存在冒犯了你\n你可以随便离开
If her presence offends,\nyou're free to leave.
你结了婚吗？
Are you married?
没有
No.
为什么没有？你等着坠入爱河？
Why not? Are you waiting to fall in love?
-不是\n-好了
- No.\n- Good.
浪漫的爱情\n是旧社会的最后幻想
Romantic love will be\nthe last illusion of the old order.
你应该与农民结婚
You should marry one of your peasants.
是，我真的应该
Yes. I damn well should.
人类的手足情谊！
The brotherhood of man!
尼古拉，你需要看医生
Nikolai, you need to see a doctor.
然后来博斯高和我一起住\n直至你健康
Then come and stay with me at Pokrovskoe\ntill you get your health back.
与我妻子一起吗？
With my wife?
如果你…
If you...
或者…
Or...
或出国去泡温泉
Or go abroad to a spa.
我会送更多来，如果你要的话
I'll send more if that's what you want.
你好，这是什么？
Hello, what's this?
奥地利皇室来渡蜜月\n我接待他们四天
Austrian royalty on their honeymoon.\nI've got them for four days.
私人马车停在月台对面
The private carriage will\nstop opposite the stand.
倒霉，他们喜欢什么，艺术吗？
Bad luck. What do they like, art?
食品
Food.
火车到了
Here's the train.
Oh.
我会回来
I'll come back.
史蒂华！
Stiva!
安娜！
Anna!
-你看来不惭愧！\n-噢，我真的惭愧
- You don't look ashamed!\n- Oh, I am, I really am.
是的，奥布隆斯基的妹妹，卡列尼娜
Yes, of course. Oblonsky's\nsister, Karenina.
很女人味，对吗？
Charmante, don't you think?
伯爵夫人
There, Countess.
你找到了儿子\n我也找到了我哥哥
You have found your son,\nand I have found my brother.
卡列尼娜女士也有一个儿子
Madam Karenina has a son, too.
这是他们第一次分开\n所以她很忧心
It's the first time they've been apart,\nso she frets about him.
对不起，我之前不认识你
Excuse me for not recognizing you before.
-再见，伯爵夫人\n-再见，亲爱的
- Au revoir,  Countess.\n- Au revoir,  my dear.
让我吻你漂亮的脸
Let me kiss that pretty face.
把人们留在里面，直到此清理好
Keep your people inside\nuntil this has been cleared up.
他们说他是个大家庭的\n唯一支柱
The sole supporter of a\nlarge family, they say.
那么，能不能为他们做点事？
Well, can't anything be done for them?
妈妈，等一等我
Wait for me, Maman.
退后，让开一边，退后
Stand back.\nMove aside. Stand back.
为此要感谢你了
I have you to thank for that.
噢，太好人了！
Oh! Oh, what a good fellow!
真是个好人
What a good fellow.
你认识弗龙斯基伯爵很久吗？
Have you known Count Vronsky long?
你喜欢他？他爱上基蒂
Did you like him? He's in love with Kitty.
Oh.
但我们应该讨论你和多莉
But we should be discussing you and Dolly.
你有什么好说呢？
What have you got to say for yourself?
我已经说过一切了，还跪下流泪
I've said it all. On my knees, in tears.
现在需要你去说
Now I need you to say it.
我会去办公室\n你便可单独和多莉谈
I'm going to the office,\nso you'll have Dolly to yourself.
不要晚回家
Don't be late home.
天啊
Oh, dear.
基蒂将会来见你
Kitty's coming by to see you.
她已长大成人了\n有点怕你
She's all grown up\nand a bit frightened of you.
圣彼得堡社交圈的美女
The belle of St. Petersburg society.
我是吗？
Is that who I am?
多莉
Dolly.
史蒂华已经告诉我
Stiva has told me.
多莉，很抱歉
Oh, Dolly, I'm sorry.
发自我心底的
From the bottom of my heart.
我不知道该怎么做
I don't know what to do.
我明白、我明白
I know. I know.
我不能忍受和他在一起
I can't bear to be with him.
他不在乎，他已得到了想要的东西
And he doesn't care.\nHe's got what he wants.
他想要的是你，多莉，他爱你
What he wants is you. He loves you, Dolly.
你和孩子们是他的一切
You and the children\nare everything to him.
是吗？
Are we?
还要搞一个家庭教师？
And there is room for a governess?
那样很可耻、羞耻\n但那种不是爱
That was shameful,\ndisgraceful, but it was not love.
那是男人的兽性，而不是他的心
It was the animal in man, not the soul.
史蒂华的后悔是来自内心的
Stiva's remorse is from the soul.
那么，我呢？
Well, what about me?
他的后悔会令我舒服点吗？
Does his remorse make it easier for me?
我知道你很难受\n但是，多莉，你要告诉我
I know you are suffering.\nBut, Dolly, you must tell me.
你的心是否仍爱他？\n足以原谅他呢？
Is there enough love left in your heart?\nEnough to forgive him?
当我想到他们在一起\n我无法原谅他
Well, when I think of them together,\nI can't forgive him.
不
No.
可怜的，所以你宁愿接受命运？
My poor lamb.\nSo you would rather accept your fate?
我的命运？
My fate?
但我什么也没做过！是他…
But I haven't done anything!\nIt's him who...
多莉，你爱他吗？
Do you love him, Dolly?
你爱他，他爱你
You love him, and he loves you.
但你不能原谅他
But you can't forgive.
你们的生活永远这样继续下去\n大家都很可怜
So, your lives must continue like this\nforever, with both of you wretched.
很漂亮，这是婚纱吗？
Oh, that's pretty. Is\nthat a wedding dress?
是的
Yes.
找“格里沙”的“格”字
Look for the "G" for "Grisha."
这里
- Here.\n- Oh.
你可以找你的全名吗？
Can you do your whole name?
那看起来像个公主吗？不？
Doesn't that look like a princess? No?
我回来了！家、家！
I'm home! Home, home, home!
我的孩子们在哪里？
Now, where are my little ducklings?
爸爸！爸爸！
Papa! Papa!
爸爸！
Papa!
安娜，你会留下来\n参加波里舒卓夫的舞会吗？
Will you stay\nfor the Bobrishchevs' ball, Anna?
我在舞会总是感觉沉闷
Oh. I always feel dull at a ball.
Ah!
史蒂华，告诉安娜她一定要来舞会
Stiva, tell Anna she\nmust come to the ball.
当然她必须来
Well, of course she must.
神与你同在
And God go with you.
你可以给我介绍你的新家庭教师
You can introduce me\nto your new governess.
但她很老！她有100岁
But she's old! She's a hundred!
我知道你为什么要我来
I know why you want me to come.
你希望每个人都在那里
You want everyone to be there
因为你很肯定\n那晚你是主角
because you're quite sure\nit's going to be your night.
你怎么知道的？
How did you know?
弗龙斯基
我知道一切
I know everything.
噢，如再是你的年纪
Oh, to be your age again.
被那…
Surrounded by that...
那蓝色的薄雾环绕
That blue mist.
我结婚时也是18岁
I was 18, too, when I got married.
王子在家吗？
Is the prince at home?
我相信他刚上楼
He's just gone up, I believe.
没人来接待吗？
Is nobody receiving?
我可以去咨询，先生，应该没有了
I can enquire, sir. I don't think so.
公主提早休息\n有口讯吗？
The princess retired early.\nIs there a message?
没有，谢谢
No. Thank you.
我们以为你结了婚回来
We thought you would come back married.
是吗？
Did you?
但你只带一顶帽子回来
But you only came back with a hat.
黑色丝质帽子
A black silk hat.
你可以用什么动物\n来做这样的帽子？
What kind of animal\ncan you make a hat like that from?
这不是天然的
It's not natural.
或许下一次
Next time, perhaps.
不会有下一次
There'll be no next time.
基蒂
Kitty.
与我跳华尔兹吗？
May I have a waltz?
好的，鲍里斯
You may, Boris.
我会留第三只舞给你\n只因这是你第一次来舞会
I'll save you the third,\njust because it's your first ball.
你是我第一个征服的人！
You're my first conquest!
你要被带到哪里？
Where do you want to be taken?
那里
There.
史蒂华，你好吗？
How are you, Stiva?
感谢安娜\n我很快乐，你想跳舞吗？
Thanks to Anna, I am a happy man.\nWould you like to dance?
不，请安娜跳吧
No. Ask Anna.
不，我不…
No, I don't...
-那么，来吧\n-噢！小心！
- Come on, then.\n- Oh! Look out!
你这种卑鄙、愚蠢的红娘手法
This vile, idiotic matchmaking of yours.
天啊，我做错什么？
For goodness' sake, what have I done?
有什么事吗？
Is anything the matter?
没有
No.
基蒂公主，你永远都看来很可爱
You look as lovely as\never, Princess Kitty.
妈妈，不要问我
Don't ask me, Maman.
基蒂，下一只是我们的舞
Kitty, it's us next.
公主，我有幸能与你跳这只舞
Princess, I have the\nhonor to claim my dance.
他会与基蒂跳玛祖卡舞，你等着看
He'll dance the mazurka with Kitty.\nYou'll see.
我是！我真的是！
I am! I really am!
跟我跳舞
Dance with me.
我不习惯跟在火车站
I'm not used to being spoken to like that
见过一次面的男人这样说话
by a man I met once at a railway station.
我敢说，如果我不能和你跳舞
I dare say, but if I'm\nnot to dance with you,
我便会离开此舞会回家
then I'm getting out of this operetta\nand going home.
那么，就为了基蒂吧
Then, for Kitty's sake.
那个是我妹妹
That's my sister.
下一站是博洛戈耶！\n下一站，博洛戈耶
Next stop is Bologoye!\nBologoye, next stop.
我可以为你服务吗？
Can I be of service to you?
为什么你要离开莫斯科？
Why are you leaving Moscow?
我还可以做什么？
What else can I do?
我要与你一起
I have to be where you are.
停止，够了
Stop, that's enough.
回到基蒂身边
Go back to Kitty.
不
No.
这是错的
This is wrong.
没有什么分别
It makes no difference.
你没有权这样
You have no right.
没有什么分别
It makes no difference.
你必须忘了我
You must forget me.
如果你是个好人\n你会忘记一切
If you're a good man,\nyou'll forget everything.
而你呢？你会忘记吗？
And you? Will you forget?
我会
Yes.
史奥沙没事吧？
Is Serozha all right?
噢，就是这样对我？
Oh, is that all I get?
他没事，很好
Yes, he's quite well.
你很成功
Were you a success?
我？
I?
噢，多莉和史蒂华
Oh, Dolly and Stiva.
是的，我想很成功
Yes, I think so.
-我会自己宣布名字\n-好的，先生
- I'll announce myself.\n- Very good, sir.
原来是弗龙斯基
Vronsky. The master himself.
男爵夫人，为弗龙斯基伯爵\n用新咖啡壶弄咖啡
Baroness, coffee from\nthe new coffee pot for Count Vronsky.
如果我阻住你，我会回家
I'll be off home if I'm in the way.
男爵夫人，你身在家里
You're at home where you are, Baroness.
皮埃尔，你从来不向我说\n这样漂亮的话
Oh! Oh, Pierre, you never say\nsuch pretty things to me.
我们只是在讨论我的丈夫
We were just discussing my husband.
他不会和我离婚\n你知道原因吗？
He won't divorce me, you see,\nand do you know why?
-不\n-因为他喜欢用我家的银餐具
No.\nBecause he likes eating\noff my family silver.
我想提出诉颂
I want to bring an action.
尽管我是不忠
Just because I'm supposed\nto be unfaithful,
我不明白为何\n要我用皮埃尔的陶餐具
I don't see why I have to\neat off Pierre's crockery.
看看这个！
Look at it!
这是我的陶餐具
It's my crockery.
Oh!
莫斯科怎样？
How was Moscow?
很省级化
Provincial.
感谢给我的礼物
Thank you for my presents.
我在写信给多莉和基蒂
I'm writing to Dolly and to Kitty.
你真好
You are good.
睡觉时候
Time for bed.
他们在莫斯科对新法规有何说法？
What are they saying in Moscow\nabout the new statute?
什么新法规？
What new statute?
我在议会进行的新法规
The new statute I carried in Council.
没有人提到
No one mentioned it.
真的吗？
Really?
Oh.
在这里引起了轰动
Here, it caused quite a sensation.
贝西公主
Princess Betsy.
表哥
Cousin.
我不知道你是艺术爱好者
I didn't know you were an art lover.
我准备好做艺术爱好者
I'm prepared to be one.
莉迪亚伯爵夫人告诉我
Countess Lydia tells me
自从你回来后\n没有到过她的晚上聚会
you haven't been to\none of her evenings since you returned.
上次是见一位传教士
The last one was to meet a missionary.
再之前是
The one before that
一个讲座有关\n希腊和罗马教会的联合
was for a lecture on\nthe union of the Greek and Roman Churches.
对不起
Oh, I'm sorry.
我知道你喜欢她
I know you're fond of her.
来吧，我们迟到了
Come on, or we'll be late.
弗龙斯基，事情是这样的
Here's the thing, Vronsky.
有一个空缺出现\n而且对你是个晋升机会
A posting's come up,\nand there's a promotion in it for you.
长官，谢谢你
Thank you, sir.
在塔什干的驻军内
In the garrison in Tashkent.
塔什干？但是…
Tashkent? But...
如果你不介意的话\n我想留在圣彼得堡
I would like to stay in Peter, sir,\nif you don't mind.
我不介意
Well, I don't mind.
但你的母亲…这是她的主意
But your mother... It's her idea.
你丈夫是一个圣人
Your husband is a saint,
为了俄国的缘故\n我们必须好好珍惜他
and we must all cherish him\nfor Russia's sake.
你没有来我的晚宴
You didn't come to my dinner.
我要见我的指挥官
I had to see my Commanding Officer.
“她”也没有来
Well, "she" didn't come either.
我希望你能之后来
I do hope you can come on afterwards.
纪思道神父的中国传道报告\n将会有幻灯片看
Father Kristof's report on the Chinese\nmission will be with lantern slides.
我要去维士盖家
I'm expected at the Tverskoys'.
是吧
No doubt.
但我敢肯定\n贝西公主可以等你的
But I'm sure that\nPrincess Betsy can wait for you.
是，其实，我不会去贝西那里
Yes, in fact, I don't think\nI will go to Betsy's.
你被捉到了
You're caught.
我怕我越来越荒谬
I'm afraid I'm becoming quite ridiculous.
现在有一种现象
Now, there's a phenomenon.
你看，安娜的影子\n在安娜到之前已到了
Look, Anna's shadow\nhas arrived before Anna.
我是安娜的朋友
I'm Anna's friend.
但是在公众做决定
But all this making up\none's mind to it in public
对一个像卡列宁的\n杰出男人来说，是毫不客气
is not polite to\na distinguished man like Karenin.
以我看来，卡列宁是个笨蛋\n安娜是我们最好的
In my opinion, Karenin is a fool\nand Anna is the best of us.
公主，我们都爱你的相反意见
And we all love you for your\ncontrary opinions, Princess.
阿历士，你看来很绝望
Alexei, you look desperate.
这样不好看的
It's not attractive.
我正失去希望
I'm losing hope.
什么希望？
Hope of what?
说服一个贤惠的女人\n打破她的婚姻誓言？
Persuading a virtuous woman\nto break her marriage vows?
不，你是对的
No, you're right.
她不会来的
She won't come.
他已经走了
He's gone.
但你来得及那惊喜
But you're just in time for the surprise.
转头！
Turn around!
我可否为你拿些冰来？
May I have the honor\nof bringing you an ice?
现在有冰吃
Ices are being served.
我宁愿尝试香烟
I would prefer to try a cigarette.
Courage.
有机会我会试另一口
I'll try another one sometime.
在何时？
When?
在哪里？
Where?
我还以为自莫斯科后\n你的态度有所改善
Just as I was thinking\nyour manners had improved since Moscow.
你的表现很差
You behaved badly.
非常差
Very badly.
又是谁造成的呢？
And who was responsible for that?
给我一杯茶
Give me a cup of tea.
太好了！
How nice!
阿历士亚历山祖维治到了
Alexei Alexandrovich has arrived.
我不知道这刻\n我能否忍受多一个阿历士
I'm not sure my nerves\ncan stand another Alexei at this moment.
你是否高兴见到我？
Were you glad to see me or not?
舒士堡家庭曾邀请我们吃晚餐
So the Schuzburgs asked us to dinner.
听说酱汁花费一千卢布\n但味道很可怕
The sauce was said to have cost a\nthousand rubles, and it was ghastly.
我给了他们一种\n值85戈比的酱汁，却很美味
I gave them a sauce\nthat cost 85 kopeks and it was a triumph.
这必须停止
This must stop.
你让我觉得\n好像犯了某种罪
You make me feel\nas if I were guilty of something.
你要我怎办？
What do you want me to do?
我要你去莫斯科\n乞求基蒂原谅你
I want you to go to Moscow\nand beg Kitty to forgive you.
不，这不是你想要的
No, that's not what you want.
莫斯科？我可以有更好的
Moscow? I can do better than that.
我今晚拒绝了调职到塔什干
Tonight I refused a posting to Tashkent.
我可以改变主意\n你将永远不再见到我
I can change my mind,\nand you'll never see me again.
如果你有为我着想\n你会还我安宁
If you have any thought for me,\nyou will give me back my peace.
我没有安宁可以给你
I have no peace to give.
我们不可能有安宁
There can be no peace for us.
只有痛苦或最大的幸福
Only misery or the greatest happiness.
你的丈夫是不可能的
Your husband is impossible.
他所有观点都错
His opinions are all wrong,
但是他说话如此出色\n每次争论他都赢
but he talks so brilliantly,\nhe wins every argument.
什么？
What?
我来带你回家
I called to take you home.
不，我要留下
No, I'm staying.
派马车回来接我吧
Send the carriage back for me.
好的
Of course.
你要我去塔什干吗？
Do you want me to go to Tashkent?
我会去塔什干
So I'll go to Tashkent.
不！
No!
我不想你去
I don't want you to go.
我没睡等你谈谈
I stayed up to talk to you.
关于什么事？
What about?
现在很晚了
It's late.
安奴舒卡在哪？
Where's Annushka?
我已送走她
I sent her off.
嗯
Well.
如果你想谈，但我们应该睡觉了
If you want to talk, but\nwe should go to bed.
我必须提醒你一件事
I must warn you about something.
提醒我？
Warn me?
真的很夜了
Oh, it's really rather late.
我想提醒你\n你可能轻率和疏忽下
I wish to warn you that\nyou may, inadvertently
无意中给全世界
by indiscretion and carelessness,
有机会谈论你
give the world occasion to talk about you.
我不是一个委员会
I am not a committee.
请说你想告诉我什么
Please say what you want to tell me.
你和弗龙斯基伯爵\n今晚引人注意
You and Count Vronsky\nattracted attention tonight.
当我不与人交谈，你不喜欢
You don't like it when I\ndon't talk to people,
我与人交谈你又不喜欢
and you don't like it when I do.
我自己没有注意到什么
I didn't notice anything myself,
但我看见各人都注意到
but I saw everyone else noticed.
我认为嫉妒\n对你是侮辱和贬低我
I consider jealousy to be insulting\nto you and degrading to me.
我无权问你的感受
I have no right to inquire\ninto your feelings.
这只与你的良知有关
They concern only your conscience.
但我有责任提醒你\n我们是神联系在一起的
But it's my duty to remind you\nthat we are bound together by God,
而这种联系\n只能被反对神的罪打断
and this bond\ncan only be broken by a crime against God.
我没有什么要对你说
I have nothing to say to you.
你有一个儿子的
And you have a son.
我很累了
And I'm tired.
如果我错了，请你原谅
If I am wrong, I ask your pardon.
我不知道你在说什么
I don't know what you're talking about,
真的太夜了
and it's really too late for this.
请原谅我
Excuse me, please.
为时已晚
Too late.
上帝！噢，原谅我吧！
Oh, God! Oh, forgive me!
一切都完了
It's the end of everything.
除了你\n我现在一无所有了，记住这一点
I've got nothing left now except you,\nremember that.
我怎能忘记？
How could I not remember?
你是我的幸福
You're my happiness.
幸福？
Happiness?
你杀了我的幸福
You murdered my happiness.
凶手
Murderer.
继续
Go on.
是的
Yes.
继续吧，凶手
Go on. Murderer.
凶手
Murderer.
看，它们来了
Look out, here they come.
噢，倒霉
Oh, bad luck.
Potage aux choux à la russe!
亚加菲亚，如果你在莫斯科开餐馆
Agafia, if you opened up in Moscow,
英伦餐馆会关门
the l'Angleterre would go out of business.
这是真的
It's true.
-你想知莫斯科的新闻吗？\n-巴比伦？不想
- Do you want news of Moscow?\n- Babylon? No.
对了，你不在乎吧？
Oh, you're right, what do you care?
你爱乡村，你得到了
You love the country, you've got it.
你爱农业，你得到了
You love agriculturing,\nand, Lord knows, you've got that.
你喜欢射击，你得到了
You love shooting, you've got that.
你已经得到想要的一切
- You've got everything you want.\n- Ha!
好了，继续说
All right, go on, then.
你有没有停止偷面包？
Have you stopped stealing bread rolls?
芭蕾女郎，东方型，我怎能抗拒？
Ballet girl, Oriental type.\nHow can I help it?
想知…
How is...
舒巴斯基家庭好吗？
How are the Shcherbatskys?
你意思是基蒂
You mean Kitty.
-她订了婚吗？\n-没有
- Is she engaged now?\n- No.
弗龙斯基返回圣彼得堡
Vronsky went back to St. Petersburg.
Huh.
基蒂夏天将会在\n亚高素禾见多莉
Kitty will be seeing\nDolly at Ergoshovo in the summer.
你可以…
You could...
噢，我夏天没有时间
Oh, yes, as if I had time in the summer.
我今年在卡辛\n有额外土地要制干草
And I've got extra land\nat Kashin this year for the haymaking.
卡辛？那不是在亚高素禾道吗？
Kashin? That's on the\nErgoshovo road, isn't it?
基蒂在时，可以去见她
Couldn't you see Kitty when she's there?
更加不能\n我曾侮辱了自己
Especially, not then. I\nhumiliated myself once.
你真该死，康斯亚，你爱基蒂的
Oh, damn you, Kostya. You love Kitty.
你爱基蒂而你不能原谅她
You love Kitty and you can't forgive her
是因为，第一，你怯懦\n然后你搞糟了
because, first, you funked it,\nand then you bungled it.
然后你逃避一个18岁的女孩
And then you ran away\nfrom an 18-year-old girl
她却被一个军人愚弄了
who was made a fool of by a uniform.
我不同情你，我同情基蒂
It's not you I feel sorry for, it's Kitty.
她的心拒绝我
Her heart told her no.
你来猎鹬或批评我？
Did you come to shoot\nsnipe or criticize me?
不要像包裹般抱他
Well, don't hold him like a parcel.
噢！亲爱的，是基蒂阿姨
Oh! It's Aunt Kitty, darling.
他是否令你羞耻\n纠缠于你的烦恼？
Doesn't he make you ashamed\nof dwelling on your troubles?
我没有烦恼
I have no troubles.
不值得为那个男人流泪\n请相信我
That man wasn't worth\nthe tears, believe me.
我不关心他\n我甚至没有想及他或她
I don't care about him.\nI don't even think about him, or her.
除了恨她
Except to hate her.
那么我们永不再谈这事了
Then we'll never speak of it again.
有更好的男人等着你
There are better men waiting for you.
史蒂华说…
Stiva says...
基蒂，亲爱的，康斯坦丁有否…
Kitty, my lamb, did Konstantin...
与列文有何关系？
What has Levin got to do with it?
无论如何，我永远不会结婚
Anyway, I'll never get married.
这一切已令我很恶心
The whole business of it\nhas become disgusting to me.
看你得到了什么\n为何他们称之为爱情？
And look what it's done for you.\nWhy do they call it love?
因为这就是爱
Because it's love.
我要你这样，我不在乎
I want you to, I don't care about it.
你应该在乎
You should care.
总之，可能有人在监视着
Anyway, someone might be watching.
但反正我已被诅咒
But I'm damned, anyway.
我不是，我很有福
I'm not. I'm blessed.
-你爱我\n-是的
- You love me.\n- Yes.
-只有我\n-不
- Only me.\n- No.
-除了芙芙？\n-对
- Apart from Frou-Frou?\n- Yes.
但爱我多过爱你的马？
But me more than your horse?
是
Yes.
你开心吗？
Are you happy?
开心
Yes.
你爱我吗？
And you love me?
爱
Yes.
有多少？
How much?
这么多
This much.
这么多？
This much?
是
Yes.
-这么多？\n-是
- This much?\n- Yes.
这么多？
And this much?
是
Yes.
这么多？
This much?
是
Yes.
这么多？和这么多？
This much? And this much?
这就是爱吧
So, this is love.
这样
This.
伯爵夫人
Countess.
我以为你会在彼得霍夫
I thought you would be at Peterhof now.
我从那里来的
I've come from there.
我很苦恼\n你今年没有住在你平时的房子
I'm distressed that you haven't\ntaken your usual house this year.
安娜想改变一下
Anna wanted a change.
更接近在沙士高史鲁的\n贝西公主
Nearer to Princess Betsy at Tsarskoe Selo.
那些卫兵就在沙士高的夏令营
The guards are in summer camp at Tsarskoe.
阿历士亚历山祖维治
Alexei Alexandrovich,
原谅我，但是…
forgive me, but...
你太宽容，你的妻子…
You are too tolerant. Your wife is...
这是有关我的妻子吗？
Oh! Is this about my wife?
我的妻子是无可非议的
My wife is beyond reproach.
毕竟，她是我的妻子
She is, after all, my wife.
阿遼沙！阿遼沙！
Alyosha! Alyosha!
来自妈妈的口讯
A message from Maman.
她的朋友索罗金娜公主\n在这里有间房子
Her friend Princess\nSorokina has a house here
和一个处女的女儿
and a virgin daughter.
嗯，这不是口讯的一部份
Well, that's not part of the message,
但他们将会全部出席比赛
but they'll all be at the races
和赛后预你去吃晚餐
and you're expected to supper afterwards.
先生们！先生们！
Gentlemen! Gentlemen!
我们为军团干杯！
I give you the regiment!
为军团干杯！
The regiment!
我听说你拒绝了晋升
I heard you turned down a promotion.
那是受到妈妈干预的
That was Maman  interfering.
是
Yes.
而现在她找到一个公主给你
And now she's come up\nwith a princess for you.
阿历士，我们是兄弟\n所以不要见怪
Alexei, we're brothers,\nso don't take offense.
结婚能把包伏放到背上
Getting married puts\nthe pack on your back.
让你的手可以自由攀登阶梯
It leaves your hands free\nfor climbing the ladder.
与有夫之妇太认真
Getting serious about a married woman
就像拿着包伏在你的怀里
is like carrying your pack in your arms.
他们谈论我
So, they talk about me.
萨沙，我快要离开
I'm leaving, Sasha.
有个指派？
An assignation?
来吧，我会向你介绍
Come on, I'll introduce you.
很美丽
Beautiful.
人不会伤害的
A man would come to no harm.
你认为你明天会赢吗？
Do you think you'll win tomorrow?
马高田的角斗士是最热门的
Makhotin's Gladiator is favorite.
十六手
Sixteen hands.
芙芙在他身旁看得很纤小
Frou-Frou looks dainty beside him.
但她有内涵
But she's got heart.
对吗，亲爱的？
Haven't you, my darling?
安娜
Anna.
阿历士！
Alexei!
什么事？
What is it?
我无法忍受\n在比赛前不见你
I couldn't bear not to\nsee you before the race.
你在想什么？
What were you thinking about?
告诉我
Tell me.
我怀了孕
I'm pregnant.
噢，我的爱人
Oh, my love.
对我们来说\n爱从来不是一个游戏
Well, love was never a game to us.
现在终于无须生活在角落里
Here's an end to living in corners,
每一天存在于谎言中
existing day to day on lies.
好
Yes.
现在我们可以在一起了
Now we can be together.
阿历士，我们怎能呢？
How can we, Alexei?
告诉卡列宁一切
Tell Karenin everything.
你认为我丈夫\n会让你做我的礼物？
Do you think my husband\nwill make you a present of me?
离开他
Leave him.
离开他，做你的情妇？
Leave him and be your mistress?
是的，远走高飞
Yes, run away.
我再也见不到我的儿子
I would never see my son again.
法律是由丈夫和父亲们制造出来的
The laws are made by husbands and fathers.
那么怎样？
What, then?
你不快乐\n我会永远不能原谅自己
I'll never forgive myself\nfor your unhappiness.
不快乐？
Unhappiness?
我就像一个饥饿的乞丐\n有人给我食物
I'm like a starving beggar\nwho's been given food.
我，不快乐？
I, unhappy?
不是
No.
这就是我的快乐
This is my happiness.
史奥沙！
Serozha!
史奥沙，我来捉你！
Serozha, I'm coming to get you!
你在哪里？
Where are you?
史奥沙！
Serozha!
你在哪里？
Where are you?
小伙子，你好吗？
How are you, young man?
似乎见不到你的导师
Your tutor doesn't seem to be in evidence.
Yah!
阿历士
Alexei.
你终于可脱身，你能留下来吗？
You got away at last. Can you stay?
为什么？
Why?
你去找华西里卢奇治
Go and find Vasily Lukich.
我要换衣服
I have to change.
贝西公主\n会派马车来接我
Princess Betsy is sending her trap for me.
你想来吗？\n她带我去参观赛事
Would you like to come?\nShe's taking me to watch the race.
赛事，好的
Races, surely.
不，我会稍后来\n然后我必须回城
No, I'll come on later.\nThen I must get back to town.
好！
Yes!
公主！公主！
Princess! Princess!
打赌！下一场你看中了谁？
A bet! Who do you fancy in the next?
古苏洛夫
Kusolev.
我赌弗龙斯基，一双手套好吗？
I'm on Vronsky. Pair of gloves?
一言为定
Done.
阿历山大弗龙斯基
Alexander Vronsky.
你很精致
You are an exquisite creature.
你真的应该是\n今天胜利的战利品
You really ought to be\nthe spoils of victory today.
Yah! Yah!
加油，芙芙！加油！
Go, Frou-Frou! Go!
加油！
Go!
加油，芙芙！加油！
Go, Frou-Frou! Go!
阿历士！
Alexei!
我在此
I'm here.
Oh.
我在此
I'm here.
起来！
Get up!
她的背折断了
Her back is broken.
你知道…
You know...
他们说皇帝不赞成赛事
They say the Emperor\ndisapproves of the races.
因为受伤的危险
The danger of injury.
不过我…
But I...
什么？
What?
我意思是我觉得\n军队的男子汉运动，有一个价值
I'm saying I think there's\na value in manly sport, for the military.
我不明白
I don't understand.
在我看来\n不是运动本身，是那种场面
In my opinion, it's not the sport itself.\nIt's the spectacle.
一个残酷的场面…
It's making a cruel spectacle out of...
你在说什么？
What are you talking about?
-我要告诉你…\n-是
- I have to tell you...\n- Yes.
我要告诉你\n你今天的表现不恰当
I have to tell you,\nyou behaved improperly today.
怎样不恰当？
How is that?
当一个骑手跌倒时\n公开表露你的感觉
By making plain your feeling\nwhen one of the riders fell.
你的行为是不恰当的
Your conduct was improper.
不能再这样发生\n我以前曾说过的
It must not occur again.\nI have said it before.
你可能说我的关注\n是不必要和荒谬的
You will say my concern\nis unnecessary and ridiculous.
你是我的妻子
You are my wife.
我这样想是错的
I'm wrong to think that.
是吗？
Yes?
也许我错了…
Perhaps I was mistaken...
不
No.
你没有弄错
You were not mistaken.
我爱他
I love him.
我是他的情妇
I am his mistress.
你想怎样处置我也好
Do what you like to me.
等等，请走开
Wait. Please, move away.
我不会有丑闻的\n因此你不能再见他
I will not have a scandal. Therefore,\nyou will not see this man again.
你会表现到若无其事\n像社会上的人或仆人
You will behave in a way\nthat nothing is known against you
不知道你的丑闻
by society or by the servants.
作为回报，你将继续有\n妻子的权利和职责
In return, you will keep\nthe privileges of a wife, and the duties.
明天你会回家，就是这样了
Tomorrow you will return home.\nThat is all.
你有受伤吗？
Are you hurt?
发生了什么？
What's happened?
我告诉他我是你的情妇
I told him I'm your mistress.
他以为我可以放弃你还活下去
He thinks I can give you\nup and go on living.
你不能
No. You cannot.
是时候上床睡觉？
Time for bed?
很高兴听见你被人祝贺\n有关你的丈夫
It was pleasant to hear\nyou being congratulated on your husband.
我不是在乎勋章，但…
Not that I care for decorations, but...
阿历士，我不能，对不起
Alexei, I can't. I'm sorry.
Oh.
我现在是他的妻子
But I'm his wife, now.
我有了他的孩子
I'm having his child.
告诉我，我做了什么而有这结果
Tell me what I did to deserve this.
停！
Halt!
西奥多，有多少个割草人？
How many mowers is it, Theodore?
42个，主人
Forty-two, Master.
在你父亲的时期\n这是30个人两天的工作
In your father's time,\nit was work for two days for 30 men.
他自己从来没有拿起镰刀
Though he never picked\nup a scythe himself.
他们不喜欢我这样
The men don't like me for it.
他们喜欢习惯了的方式
They like what they're used to.
这样能安定我
It settles me.
主人，为何会呢？
How is that, Master?
当我割草，我不问自己\n在这里的原因
When I'm mowing,\nI don't ask myself why I'm here.
你在这里做主人\n康斯坦丁德米特里维治
You're here to be\nMaster Konstantin Dmitrievich.
藉神的恩典，一直以来都是这样
As it's always been, by the grace of God.
西奥多，我的父亲拥有你
My father owned you, Theodore.
你就如物件般可被买卖
Owned you like chattels\nto be bought and sold.
这是神的恩典吗？
Was that by the grace of God?
是的
It was.
你看着那个就是我最小的儿子
That's my youngest\nyou were looking at, there.
现在他的生活岌岌可危\n自从有了自由，便必须找工作
His young life is perilous now since the\nfreedom came and work must be found.
他们看起来比我更快乐
They look happier than I've ever been.
我是否在寻找简单的生活？
Is it living simply that I'm looking for?
有预期我到的
I'm expected.
不
No.
我不要这样活下去
I will not live like this.
这样时刻在等候
This waiting for hour after hour,
不知何时我有机会再见你
not knowing when I'll ever see you again.
对不起
Sorry.
这是我的恶魔，我无法控制
It's my demon. I can't help it.
你写字条说你病了
You wrote that you were ill.
别担心，我命不久已
Don't worry, it won't be for long.
-停止\n-不，这是真的
- Stop.\n- No, it's true.
在梦里有人告诉我的
I was told it in a dream.
看，只是一个恶梦
There. It was only a bad dream.
是，我只不过会\n怀着你的孩子死去
Yes, and I'm only\ngoing to die having your baby.
-这是无稽之谈\n-告诉我是真的
- That's all nonsense.\n- Tell me it is.
告诉我是真的
Tell me it is.
你只爱我一个
You love me, only me.
你的字条说你丈夫会不在家的
Your note said your husband would be out.
他迟了，他自讨的
He was late. It serves him right.
而你…
And you...
为什么称他为我丈夫？
Why do you call him my husband?
他不是我丈夫，他是个时钟
He isn't my husband, he's a clock.
但这很尴尬，我的名誉\n你做了协议
But it was awkward. My honor.\nYou made an agreement.
当你与上校共享妓女时\n有想到你的名誉吗？
Do you think of your honor when you're\nsharing whores with your Colonel?
又是你的恶魔作怪？
Your demon again?
我希望你开始恨我之前\n我死了
I'll be glad to die before\nyou start to hate me.
安娜
Anna.
把你的手放在这里
Put your hand there.
你能感觉到他移动
You can feel him move.
我恭敬地问卡列宁部长
I respectfully ask Minister Karenin
他的建议有关规管这些\n富有色彩的吉普赛部落
whether his proposals for the regulation\nof these colorful gypsy tribes
及博学、虔诚的犹太人\n及…
of these scholarly,\nGod-fearing Jews, and of...
但恐怕我失去了\n部长的注意力
But I'm afraid I've lost\nthe Minister's attention.
谁在家？
Who is here?
大人，只有夫人在
Only Madame,  Your Excellency.
我想见他，因为…
I wanted to see him because...
我不想知道为何一个女人\n想见她的情人
I do not wish to know\nwhy a woman wants to see her lover.
你在做什么？
What are you doing?
我要他的信！
I want his letters!
我打算明天到莫斯科\n然后到各省
I am going to Moscow tomorrow,\nand then the provinces
与委员会一起调查犹太人\n和吉普赛人的情况
with a commission to investigate\nconditions among the Jews and gypsies,
我宁愿是他们的情况\n好过我自己的
whose conditions\nI infinitely prefer to my own.
我不会回到这个家\n直至离婚导致你潦倒街头
I will not return to this house until\ndivorce has driven you into the street.
暂时我的儿子\n将被送到我大姐那里住
Meanwhile, my son will be sent\nto live with my eldest sister.
不，阿历士，求你把史奥沙留给我
No, Alexei, please.\nPlease, leave me Serozha!
你以为我会把儿子给你！
Do you think I would let you have my son?
你这个堕落、没尊严的女人
You are depraved. A woman without honor.
感谢上帝\n我不再受爱的诅咒
I thank God the curse of\nlove is lifted from me.
我需要你的忠告
I need your advice.
-来吧！\n-是的
- Come on, come on!\n- Yes, yes.
对，跟着你走
Right, after you, after you.
-我们迟了吗？\n-当然，你迟到了
- Are we late?\n- Of course, you're late.
我是挪士顿伯爵夫人
I'm Countess Nordston.
我们去年冬天\n几乎在舒巴斯基家碰面
We nearly met at the\nShcherbatskys' last winter.
来与大家一起吧
Come into the fold.
来吧
Come on.
你们一直在等我，请原谅
You've been waiting for me. Forgive me.
基蒂在这里
Kitty is here.
康斯坦丁，我们很久没见
Konstantin, what a long time\nsince we saw each other.
自你上次见我\n但我不久前见过你
Since you saw me,\nbut I saw you not so long ago.
什么时候？
When?
你当时正驶往亚高素禾
You were driving to Ergoshovo.
我在卡辛制干草
I was at Kashin for the haymaking.
为什么你不…
Oh, but why didn't you...
我很高兴见到你
I'm so glad to see you.
你一样无变
You're just the same.
我希望不是
I hope not.
以前我年轻又愚蠢
I was young and silly in those days.
很多个月前了
Months and months ago.
而你并没有改变
And you haven't changed.
我没有
No. I haven't.
让我宣布\n有玛丽路易丝鲫鱼汤
Permit me to announce,\num, soup Marie-Louise carp
芦荀和烤牛肉
with asparagus and roast beef.
我亲身去市场买的
I went to the market in person.
加多一个位
An extra place.
我来告诉你\n我们必须切断联系
I've come to tell you\nour connection must be severed.
我要与你妹妹离婚
I'm going to divorce your sister.
离婚？
Divorce?
天啊，你在说什么？
Oh, dear me, what are you\ntalking about?
不要着急，留下来吃晚餐
Well, don't be in a hurry. Stay to dinner.
之后你可以与多莉谈
And later, you can talk\nit over with Dolly.
奥布隆斯基王子\n我们家族之间一切都完了
Prince Oblonsky,\neverything is over between our families.
阿历士，离婚是一件事\n晚餐是另一回事
Alexei, divorce is one thing.\nDinner is quite another.
你们圣彼得堡人\n相比沉闷、古板的莫斯科
You Petersburgers\nthink yourselves so de bon ton
认为自己很时髦
compared with dull, old-fashioned Moscow.
但我们知道如何办事
But we know how to do things.
有一天
Only the other day,
我听到华斯亚派耶尼哥夫\n与维斯基决斗，并杀死了他
I hear Vasya Pryachnikov\nfought a duel with Kvitsky and killed him.
是什么…
Well, what...
挑战是关于什么？
What was the challenge about?
当然是派耶尼哥夫的妻子
Pryachnikov's wife, naturally.
与名誉有关\n捍卫一个女人的名誉
It was a matter\nof honor, defending a woman's honor.
听起来像野蛮主义\n如果情人杀死了丈夫呢？
Sounds like barbarism to me.\nWhat if the lover had killed the husband?
也会保存了妻子的名誉吗？
Would that have preserved\nthe wife's honor, too?
不过，没有很多人能说\n情人为爱情而死
Still, not many of us can say\nour lover died for love.
爱情？
Love?
“不可贪图你邻居的妻子”
"Thou shall not covet\nthy neighbor's wife."
康斯坦丁德米特里维治\n你会为爱而死吗？
Would you die for love,\nKonstantin Dmitrievich?
我会，但不会为邻居的妻子
I would. But not for my neighbor's wife.
我认为不纯洁的爱就不是爱
An impure love is not love to me.
欣赏别人的妻子\n是一件好事
To admire another man's wife\nis a pleasant thing,
但为了自己利益的\n情欲沉迷就是贪婪
but sensual desire indulged\nfor its own sake is greed,
一种贪食
a kind of gluttony,
和不当地使用一些神圣的东西\n这东西被赐予给我们
and a misuse of something sacred,\nwhich is given to us
好让我们能选择一个人\n一起满足我们的人性
so that we may choose the one person\nwith whom to fulfill our humanness.
否则，我们不如做牛吧
Otherwise, we might as well be cattle.
一个理想主义者！
Ah! An idealist!
但她不会是任何人的妻子
But she will be nobody's wife.
这样会毁了她
She'll be ruined.
我试图救她，她却选择绝路
I tried to save her. She chose ruin.
阿历士亚历山祖维治
Alexei Alexandrovich.
看着我
Look at me.
你不会有安宁\n直至你原谅她
You will have no peace of mind\nuntil you forgive her.
这是安娜教懂我的
It was Anna who taught me that.
我不想原谅她
I do not wish to forgive.
我不是一个残忍的人
I'm not a cruel man.
我从来没有恨任何人
I've never hated anyone.
但我恨她入骨
But I hate her with all my soul
因为她对我的所作所为
for all the wrong she has done me.
伯爵夫人，现在轮到你\n弹奏给我们听
Now, it is\nyour turn to play us something, Countess.
我以为你不会请我弹
I thought you'd never ask.
非常好
Very good.
自从我们上次见面
Since we last met,
有件事我常常想问你
there is something I have\noften wanted to ask you.
什么事？
What is that?
这个
This.
不…
Do...
是…
Not...
是否
Did.
不是
Did not.
最后一个字是“永不”
The last word is "never."
是否“不”意思“永不”
知道
我不知道
我猜到这是说什么
I know what it says.
以前我不知道
以前
Then.
但现在呢？
But now?
你能否原谅
Can you forgive
和忘记？
and forget?
我-爱-你
我从来没有停止过
I never stopped.
我求你来吧，我需要你的原谅\n我快死了，安娜
他为什么不来呢？
Why doesn't he come?
他很仁慈，他会原谅我的
He is kind. He will forgive me.
她烧得更高
Her fever is higher.
我要阿历士，他为什么不来呢？
I want Alexei. Why doesn't he come?
给我一些水，不，我不能
Give me some water. No, I mustn't.
对我女儿不好的
It isn't good for my little girl.
或者给她一个奶妈，是的
Or let her have a nurse, yes.
不要带她来这里\n因为阿历士快到了
Don't bring her here\nbecause Alexei is coming
见到她会伤他的心
and it will hurt him to see her.
他来了，亲爱的，看那边
He's come, my dear. Look there.
对她的裁判是在上帝手中
Her deliverance\nis still in God's hands.
你认为他不会原谅我\n但你不了解他
You think he won't forgive me\nbut you don't know him.
没有人了解他除了我
No one knows him except me.
我现在不怕他
I'm not afraid of him, now.
但我怕死
I'm afraid of death, though.
Oh.
你这个可怜的男人
You poor man.
让他走近
Let him come closer.
阿历士
Alexei.
看看我的丈夫
Look at my husband.
他是一个圣人
He's a saint.
牵他的手
Take his hand.
感谢上帝
Thank God.
你现在必须离开
You must leave now.
我答应如果她要见你\n我会叫你来
I promise to send for you\nif she asks for you.
我不知道我为何这样
I don't know what happened to me.
我原谅你，我原谅安娜
I forgive you. I forgive Anna.
我的灵魂充满喜悦
My soul is filled with joy.
我将继续留在她身边\n和永远照顾她
I will remain with her\nand look after her forever.
来吧
Come now.
看看你
Look at you.
你看似你变成的东西\n一个笑柄
You look like what you've become.\nA laughingstock.
我预期你\n会被兵团解职
I fancy you will be asked\nto leave the regiment.
妈妈，我希望你离开
I would like you to go, Maman.
我准备好的时候自然会走
I'll go when I'm ready to go.
与有夫之妇有染
A little affair with a married woman
正好给年轻人教育最后一课
puts a finishing touch\nto a young man's education.
但这种病态、自私的迷恋…
But this morbid, selfish obsession...
你当众羞辱自己
You've publicly humiliated yourself
和羞辱一个\n奉献自己给俄国的人
and dishonored\na man who has devoted his life to Russia.
你最好跟我回莫斯科
So you'd better come back\nto Moscow with me.
你在这里已完蛋
You're finished here.
她的丈夫就在那里\n穿着她最好的舞会长裙
And there was her husband,\nwearing her best ball gown.
他的脸上涂满胭脂
Rouge all over his face.
Ma chère, le scandale!
但我还是告诉你一些兵团的新闻
But I'd better tell you\nsome regimental news.
谁在此？
Who is here?
大人，是伊丽莎白\n弗达洛拿维士盖公主
Princess Elisabeth\nFederovna Tverskaya, Your Excellency.
我不想见他
I don't want to see him.
但肯定你丈夫不会停止…
But surely your husband wouldn't stop...
我很高兴见到你
I'm so glad to see you.
你看似不舒服
You look feverish.
我们已经说得太多了，我要走了
We've been talking too much, so I'm going.
贝西公主来告诉我…
Princess Betsy came to tell me...
我不想向你隐瞒什么
I don't want to hide anything from you.
弗龙斯基伯爵要求来道别\n他要离开
Count Vronsky asked\nto come to say goodbye. He's going away.
我告诉他，我不能见他
I've told him that I can't receive him.
好了，再见，宝贝
Well, goodbye, my treasure.
我同意你的决定
I agree with you.
既然弗龙斯基伯爵要离开\n便没必要来
As he is going away,\nthere's no need for Count Vronsky to come.
我刚才这样说过了\n所以没必要重复说
I just said so, so there's\nno need to repeat it.
但这是由你来决定
But it is for you to decide.
是的，我决定了
Yes, and I decided.
那么我很高兴…
Then I am very glad that...
我们同意这点\n因此我们可以停止谈论它
That we agree,\nso perhaps we can stop talking about it.
好吧，有什么我能为你效劳？
Of course. Is there\nanything I can do for you?
有，求求你\n求你停止弄响你的指节
Yes, can you please, please, please\nstop cracking your knuckles?
我是个坏女人
I'm a bad woman.
但我不能呼吸
But I can't breathe.
你的仁慈，我无法赏还\n还有你的宽恕…
Your kindness, which I can't repay,\nand your forgiveness...
你求我原谅你的
You begged me for my forgiveness.
但我没有死到\n现在我必须忍受
But I didn't die, and now\nI have to live with it.
那么你想要怎样？
Then what? What do you want?
你知道你想要什么吗？\n你想见弗龙斯基伯爵？
Do you know what you want?\nDo you want to see Count Vronsky?
不是要说再见
Not to say goodbye.
我听不到
I can't hear.
不是要说再见
Not to say goodbye.
你会失去一切，永久失去
You would be lost. Irretrievably lost.
你会没有地位
You would have no position.
更糟的是，如果我们离婚\n你会是有罪的一方
And worse, if we divorce,\nyou would be the guilty party.
即是你不能合法地再婚
That means you cannot legally remarry.
你与弗龙斯基伯爵的关系\n将是非法的
Your union with Count Vronsky\nwould be illegitimate,
你的女儿也将是非法的\n而现在她有我的名来保护
as would your daughter,\nwho now has the protection of my name.
这是你想要的吗？
And this is what you want?
帮你摧毁自己\n将是一种罪过
It would be a sin to help\nyou destroy yourself.
你忘了一件事情
You forget something.
弗龙斯基伯爵和我彼此相爱
Count Vronsky and I love each other.
这爱能圣化一个罪行吗？
And this love sanctifies a criminal folly?
我只知道的是，我打发他走
All I know is that I sent him away
就好像我向自己的心开枪！
and it's as if I'd shot\nmyself through the heart!
我明白了
I see.
史奥沙呢？
And what of Serozha?
我会为他死
I would die for him,
但为了他，我不会这样活着
but I won't live like this for him.
当他认识爱情，他会原谅我的
When he knows of love, he will forgive me.
那么我必须选择较小的罪
Then I must choose the smaller sin.
即使弗龙斯基抢了我的妻子\n我依然会善待他
Vronsky has robbed me of my cloak\nand I will give him my coat.
不，我…
No, I...
爱人、爱人
My darling. My darling.
你看起来很苍白
You look so pale.
我的爱人
Oh, my darling.
我们会去南部\n那里有海洋空气和阳光
We'll go south to the\nsea air and sunshine.
这里合适吗？坐下一会
Is it all right? Sit down a minute.
我要到处看
I want to see everything.
一会儿
A moment.
现在我要做厨房女佣的工作
And now I'm doing kitchenmaid's work
因为纳迪娅的父母\n不会让她进房子
because Nadya's parents\nwon't let her set foot in the house.
谁能责怪他们呢？那是不雅的
And who can blame them? It's indecent.
我是康斯坦丁
It's Konstantin.
是的，很好
Yes, good.
这里的医生很无能
The doctor here is useless.
给我一个来自莫斯科的
Get me one from Moscow.
你去了哪儿？
Where did you go?
当我就要结婚时\n我到处问你的下落
I asked for you everywhere\nwhen I was getting married.
对不起，我不能离开他
I'm sorry. I couldn't leave him.
是，我的妻子…
Yes. My wife...
你不能留下来
You can't stay now.
我与亚加菲亚将护理他
I will nurse him with Agafia.
那女人会在村里找到地方住
The woman will find\nsomewhere in the village.
你不会见到她
You won't see her.
她知道不可能与你见面
She knows it is impossible to meet you.
我内心受到折磨\n因我带了你来这间屋
It is a torment to me\nthat I've brought you under the same roof
见到这个不幸的…这个妓女…
as this unfortunate... As this fallen...
你还身怀六甲
And in your precious, delicate condition.
康斯亚
Oh, Kostya.
好，我要干净的睡衣和床单
Good. A clean nightshirt and sheets.
一条毛巾、清洁桶和温水
A towel and a clean pail of warm water.
等一下
Wait.
还有拿瓶香水来
And bring the perfume bottle,
在我手袋外面的口袋里
in the outside pocket of my handbag.
史捷莫二十一票，卡列宁四票\n议案通过
Twenty-one to Stremov, four to Karenin.\nThe motion is carried.
阿历士，他们又回来了
Alexei, they're back.
在圣彼得堡这里
Here, in St. Petersburg.
她有写信给我
She has written to me.
给你？
To you?
他们认为我没有权利拒绝
They think I don't have\nthe right to refuse.
这是儿子的生日
It's the boy's birthday.
我的朋友
My friend,
本应要熄灭的火\n你会令它死灰复燃
you would be blowing on the embers\nof a fire which must be allowed to die.
让我写信给她
Let me write to her.
我来见史奥沙
I'm here to see Serozha.
夫人？
Madame?
对不起，大人
I beg your pardon, Your Excellency.
不，我是来见史奥沙的
No, I've come to see Serozha.
史奥沙
Serozha.
妈妈？
Maman?
Oh.
我亲爱的儿子
My dear little boy.
我知道你会来
I knew you would come.
今天是我的生日
Today is my birthday.
我知道
I know.
你在哭吗？
Are you crying?
不，我不会哭
No, I won't cry.
妈妈，你去了哪？
Where did you go, Maman?
我不知道
I don't know.
四处去，去了南部
Everywhere. The south.
我每天都在想你
I thought about you every day.
我也每天都在想你
And I thought about you every day.
你必须爱爸爸\n他比我好
And you must love Papa.\nHe's better than I am.
全世界没人比你更好
No one in the whole world\nis better than you.
不
No.
安雅在哪里？
Where's Anya?
她还在睡觉
She's still asleep.
想我替你拿外衣吗？
Should I take your coat?
夫人，你觉得不舒服？
Are you feeling unwell, madam?
我失眠
I'm not sleeping.
我可以派人去买些药
I can send out for something.
好
Yes.
你为什么在黑暗中？
Why are you in the dark?
耶士云将会拜访，你记得他吧
Yashvin is going to call.\nYou remember him.
你要出去吗？
Are you going out?
去哪？
To where?
找谁？
To whom?
有什么事？
What's the matter?
我不知道你发生了什么事
I didn't know what happened to you.
我昨天已告诉你，我的哥哥
But I told you yesterday. My brother.
是否需要整天见你的哥哥？
Does it take all day to meet your brother?
他比我更需要你吗？
Does he need you more than I do?
发生了什么事？
What's happened?
亚历山大一切都同意了
Well, Alexander agreed to everything.
母亲在莫斯科的房子归他
Mother's house in Moscow will go to him,
郊区庄园将是我们的新家
and the country estate\nwill be our new home.
一旦办好离婚
As soon as the divorce.
卡列宁还没有答你的信吗？
Karenin hasn't answered your letter yet?
自我们回来\n你是第一个来找我的人
You're the very first\nperson to call on me since our return.
我收到了贝西公主的字条
I received a note from Princess Betsy
要求我在6点30分\n至8点之间找她
asking me to call on her\nbetween 6:30 and 8:00.
或者是7点？
Or was it 7:00?
或者你们会在今晚的歌剧见
But perhaps you'll meet\nat the opera tonight.
如果我能有个箱座\n我会一定去
I would love to be there\nif I could get a box.
夫人，你的箱座是第四号
Madame,  your box is number four.
你会在那里找到我和米加雅公主
You'll find me there\nwith Princess Myagkaya.
弗龙斯基，你来吗？
Will you come, Vronsky?
-嗯…\n-我明白阿历士为何这么喜欢你了
- Well...\n- I see why Alexei is so fond of you.
你知道你不能去剧院
You know you can't go to the theater.
-安奴舒卡！\n-不要去
- Annushka!\n- For heaven's sake.
沐浴！我会来选一条裙
A bath! I'll come in and choose a dress.
安娜，我恳求你
Anna, I implore you.
我不以自己或我所做的为耻
I'm not ashamed of who I am\nor what I've done.
你为我感到羞耻吗？
Are you ashamed for me?
你不如在酒店预订房间
Why don't you book a room at the hotel?
我们不是一起吗？
Aren't we together?
你对我变了心？
Have you changed towards me?
这是因为我爱你和关心你
It's because I love you\nand care about you.
如果是这样\n为何你不跟我一起去
If that's the case, then I don't know why\nyou aren't coming with me.
这使情况更糟
- That would make it worse.\n- You're afraid.
你害怕
我不怕
Well, I'm not.
我们找人聊天，还是留在这里？
Should we visit, or stay put?
留在这里
Stay put.
部长！恭喜你
Minister! Congratulations.
过来一会吧
Come in for a moment.
索罗金娜公主和她的女儿
Princess Sorokina and her daughter.
他们来自莫斯科\n弗龙斯基伯爵母亲的邻居
They're from Moscow,\nneighbors of Count Vronsky's mother.
很有钱，没有儿子，她是个寡妇
Quite well off. No sons. She's a widow.
亲爱的，我是一本销售目录
My dear, I'm a sales catalog.
阿历士
Alexei.
完场后你会上来见我们吗？
You'll come up to see us afterwards?
我要问准华莉亚
I'll talk to Varya.
你可以探安娜吗？
Will you call on Anna?
阿历士，我喜欢…
Oh. Alexei. I'm fond of...
我的天！
For God's sake!
安娜不是罪犯
Anna isn't a criminal.
如果她只是犯了法\n我还是会找她
I'd call on her if she'd\nonly broken the law.
但是她犯了规矩
But she broke the rules.
舞台是谁布置的？\n我们没有拿节目表吗？\nthe décor? Haven't we got a program?
Who has made
上校，不介意借给我看吗？
Colonel, would you be so kind?
当然可以
Of course.
拿去吧，这是我的荣幸
Please, I would be honored\nif you would take mine.
谢谢，你真是…
Thank you. How very...
真羞耻
It's a disgrace.
细声点，这是普通的礼貌
Hush, dear. A common courtesy.
大家都在盯着
Everyone's looking.
让他们看！拿我的斗篷来
Let them look! Fetch my cloak.
我们变成什么了？
What are we coming to?
这是侮辱体统，送我回家
It's an insult to decency. Take me home.
嘘，我求求你，亲爱的\n只是说了一两句话
Hush. I beg you, my dear.\nIt was only a word or two.
我也有一两句话想跟某人说
I have a word or two for some people
我不预期在这场合\n会与这种人碰面
one didn't expect\nto be rubbing shoulders with.
她真够胆\n像个荡妇在公众卖弄自己
She has a nerve,\nflaunting herself like a slut in society.
是的，为何不去呢？
Yes, why don't you?
去救她吧，表明整件事你有份的
Rescue her and put your\nseal on the fiasco.
阿历士
Alexei,
你知道为什么她一定要离婚吧
you see why she must divorce.
婚姻会解决一切问题\n会在何时呢？
Marriage will solve everything.\nWhen will it be?
在我眼中，她是我的妻子
As far as I'm concerned, she's my wife.
正如你所见，她不是
As you saw, she isn't.
我们会到莫斯科\n然后到郊区的房子
We're going to Moscow,\nthen to my place in the country.
听起来是个好主意
That sounds like a good idea.
但有一两天，安娜会在家里
But, for a day or two,\nAnna will be at home.
所以…
Then...
我现在说再见了
I'll say goodbye now.
今晚你过得真愉快
Well, you had an excellent night.
你妈妈想你\n娶那个寡妇还是她的女儿？
Does your mother want you\nto marry the widow or the child?
-任何一个\n-不要说笑
- Either one.\n- Don't joke about it.
如果你爱我\n你就早应阻止我去！
If you loved me, you would have locked me\nin to stop me going!
是我的错
Yes, it was my fault.
我睡不到
I won't sleep.
我知道怎样令你睡
I know how to make you sleep.
吗啡
安娜，我很高兴见到你
Anna, I am very glad to see you.
你身体好吗？你的孩子如何？
Are you well? How is your little one?
史蒂华本来想请你和\n弗龙斯基伯爵来我们家
Stiva wanted to invite you\nand Count Vronsky to the house,
但是不可能
but it's impossible.
我明白的
No, I understand.
不，你不明白
No. No, you don't.
基蒂和她的丈夫来了我家
Kitty and her husband are with us.
她在莫斯科生孩子
She's in Moscow to have the baby.
基蒂！替我恭喜她
Kitty! Tell her how pleased I am.
也许我会等一两年
Perhaps I'll wait a year or two.
爱情…
Love.
是的，爱情…
Yes, love.
难道你不反对我所做的事？
Don't you disapprove of me\nfor what I've done?
不，愿我可以照样做
No. I wish I'd done the same.
不过没有人对我有兴趣
But no one asked me.
就算有，我也没胆
Well, I wouldn't have been brave enough.
你知道史蒂华
Stiva, you know,
他永远不变
he doesn't change.
就像所有男人一样
Like all men, I suppose.
吗啡
我有一个灵感
I had an inspiration.
为何要在此等？
Why do we have to wait here?
我们不如到郊区等？
Why can't we wait in the country?
我不想再听或想\n更多关于离婚的事
I don't want to hear any more about\na divorce or think about it.
好，我在此也很闷\n何时出发？
Good, I'm bored here. When should we go?
如果我在这里令你闷\n到了郊区也会一样
If I bore you here, I'll\nbore you in the country.
我不是说你，我说莫斯科很闷\n什么时候去？明天？
I didn't say you bore me, Moscow bores\nme. When should we go? Tomorrow?
我不可能明天准备好
I can't be ready by tomorrow.
-后天吧\n-好的
- The day after, then.\n- If you like.
不，等等，那是星期天\n我要去见母亲
No, wait, that's Sunday.\nI have to see Maman.
那只是20分钟火车
That's 20 minutes away on the train.
你可以明天去
You could go to see her tomorrow.
还是你想跟索罗金娜公主\n过一个星期天？
Or was it that you wanted\nto spend Sunday with Princess Sorokina?
请不要胡说
Please. Don't spoil everything.
明天去没有意思\n妈妈还未有机会看要签的文件
I can't see Maman  tomorrow\nbecause she won't have\nread the papers she has to sign.
这样的话，算了
In that case, let's not bother.
-我要星期天走，否则算了\n-真是荒谬
- I'll leave on Sunday or not at all.\n- That's absurd.
你觉得荒谬因为你不明白\n我在这里过的日子
It's absurd to you because you have\nno understanding of my life here.
-安娜\n-不，你已经不爱我了
- Anna.\n- No, you've stopped loving me.
你为了我放弃一切\n所以你讨厌我了
You've given up everything for me\nand it's turned you against me.
-为何要隐藏？\n-够了！
- Why lie about it?\n- Stop!
我只是要迟一两天出发\n你就说我不爱你
I put off our departure for a day or two\nand you tell me I don't love you.
因为我靠你的爱而活\n但爱已尽了
Because I've been living off your love\nand there's none left.
所有我们玩完了
So this is over. Finished.
对不起
I'm sorry.
我不介意我们何时去
I don't mind when we go.
我跟妈妈发电报\n我们就在星期天去
I'll telegraph Maman.  We'll go on Sunday.
你想怎样我也会照做
I'll do anything you want.
-你应该离开我\n-我不想，我爱你
- You should leave me.\n- I don't want to. I love you.
为什么？
Why?
爱情是没有“为什么”的
You can't ask "why" about love.
你收拾好了吗？
So, will you be all packed?
我要出去打点一切
I'll be out today making the arrangements.
你意思是你会在你妈的家
Is that your way of telling me\nyou'll be at your mother's
跟那个傻公主一起？
with that simpering little princess?
不，我会去见我的律师\n拿几份文件
No. I'll be at my lawyer's,\nwaiting for some documents.
跟住和几个旧同僚\n吃饭道别
Then I'm having dinner\nto say goodbye to old comrades.
我知道那目的
I know what that means.
我的天，我无法忍受了！
My God, this is unendurable!
你想的话\n我可请他们来
I can invite them here, if you like.
谢了，如果我不配在公众用餐\n我便不会与军团吃饭
Thank you, but if I'm not fit to dine\nin society, I won't eat with the band.
电报是谁发来的？
Who was the telegram from?
我没有给你看\n因为史蒂华不断说我们已知的事
I didn't show you because Stiva keeps\ntelegraphing what we already know.
卡列尼不保证任何事\n但会考虑…
Karenin promises nothing,\nbut will consider...
我已告诉你，我不在乎离婚的事\n为什么要隐藏电报呢？
I told you I don't care about the divorce,\nso why hide the telegram?
你还有什么想对我说？
Is there anything you wish to say to me?
原来是女儿
So it's the child.
她只是替妈妈把文件带来
She brought papers from Maman.
安娜
Anna.
不
No.
我的天
Oh, God.
请原谅我
Forgive me.
冬季结束之前我会买饲料
I'll be buying in feed\nbefore winter's over.
你不会迫人做得太辛苦\n你活得正直
Well, you don't press people hard,\nbut you live rightly.
你不是为了物质\n而是为了心灵
For your soul, not your belly.
我们怎样知道什么是正直？
How do we know what's rightly?
自然会知道的，还有他法？
Just by knowing it. How else?
但我相信做事要有理由
But I believe in reason.
理由，是理由令你选择这妻子吗？
Reason. Was it reason\nthat made you choose your wife?
我是来找你的
I came looking for you.
我明白了一件事情
I understood something.
你明白了什么？
What did you understand?
他对我笑了
He smiled at me.
以他的年纪，他非常懂事
He's very advanced for his age.
你明白了什么？
What did you understand?
我真为你感到骄傲
I'm so proud of you.
晚安
Night-night.
你也是
And you, too.
晚安，亲爱的儿子
Good night, my darling boy.
安雅！
Anya!